Guide to the Danny Yung Papers TAM.817
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Danny Yung Papers
1969-2022
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Yung, Danny
Yung, Eleanor
TAM.817
2.5 linear feet in 5 manuscripts, 1 small box, and 1 folder in shared housing
1.13 Gigabytes in 759 computer files
2 Reels of microfilm
Danny Yung (1943- ) is an artist, experimental filmmaker, producer, choreographer, and urban planner. Yung was a founder of The Basement Workshop, an Asian American political and arts organization for writers, visual artists, dancers, and activists. He is also the founding member and co-artistic director of Zuni Icosahedron, an experimental theater in Hong Kong where he currently lives and works. The Danny Yung Papers (dated 1969-2015) consist of materials created and collected by Yung documenting his career as an artist, experimental filmmaker, producer, choreographer, and urban planner. Materials in this collection include ephemera, correspondence, research files, original writings, and publications that document Yung's engagement with research and community outreach projects in Chinatown during the late 20th century, as well as the founding and ongoing activities of The Basement Workshop, including the publication of the organization's Bridge magazine. These materials document not only the founding and operations of Basement Workshop, but also the intersection of artistic expression, political organizing, and community activism inherent to the Asian American movement of the 1960s and 1970s. The collection also includes materials concerning the founding and ongoing activities of Zuni Icosahedron, an experimental theater in Hong Kong. This collection also includes an oral history interview with Yung predominantly focused on his involvement with The Basement Workshop.
Scope and Contents
The Danny Yung Papers (dated 1969-2015) consist of materials created and collected by Yung documenting his career as an artist, experimental filmmaker, producer, choreographer, and urban planner. Materials in this collection include ephemera, correspondence, research files, original writings, and publications that document Yung's engagement with research and community outreach projects in Chinatown during the late 20th century, as well as the founding and ongoing activities of The Basement Workshop, including the publication of the organization's Bridge magazine. These materials document not only the founding and operations of Basement Workshop, but also the intersection of artistic expression, political organizing, and community activism inherent to the Asian American movement of the 1960s and 1970s. The collection also includes materials concerning the founding and ongoing activities of Zuni Icosahedron, an experimental theater in Hong Kong. This collection also includes an oral history interview with Yung predominantly focused on his involvement with The Basement Workshop.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Eleanor Yung in October 2022; the accession number associated with this gift is 2022.086.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures.
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Biographical Note
Danny Yung (1943- ) is an artist, experimental filmmaker, producer, choreographer, and urban planner. Yung was a founder of The Basement Workshop, an Asian American political and arts organization for writers, visual artists, dancers, and activists. He is also the founding member and co-artistic director of Zuni Icosahedron, an experimental theater in Hong Kong where he currently lives and works. Since 1997, Yung has initiated several cultural and arts networks. Among them are the Asia Arts Net, Asia Performing Arts Network, and World Culture Forum.
Chinatown (New York, N.Y.); Chinese Americans.; Chinese Americans -- New York (State) -- New York.; Chinese Americans |x Social conditions |y 20th century.; Asian Americans -- Economic conditions.; Asian Americans.; Asian Americans -- New York (State) -- New York.; Yung, Eleanor; Basement Workshop
- Pre-Basement Workshop -- General, 1969-1975; cuid36865 (Box 1, Folder 1-2, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_817_ER_3)
- Chinatown Study Research, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- "Chinatown Report," Chinatown Study Group, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Chinatown Health Projects, circa 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Chinatown Project Directory, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Chinatown Community Census Committee, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- "Eat in Chinatown" Project, circa 1960s-early 1970s (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "A Demographic Study of the Chinese in the U.S.," Pao-min Chang, after 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
- US Office of Education Ethnic Heritage Studies Bill, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Basement Workshop -- General, 1971-1975; cuid36866 (Box 2, Folder 2-6, Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_817_ER_2)
- Basement Workshop -- Bridge Magazine, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
- Basement Workshop -- Bridge Magazine Microfilm, 1970-1976 (Box 5)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Bridge magazine issues are on microfilm and will require equipment in order to view.
- Basement Workshop -- Possibly Rejected Bridge Articles, circa 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 10, Box 3, Folder 1-5)
- "Asia Pacific Cultural Vision" (WFCA Report), 2004 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Zuni Icosahedron, 1993-2002 (Box 3, Folder 7-9, Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- Publications and Ephemera, 1996-2015 (Box 4, Folder 2-8, Box Shared Tamiment 164, Folder 20)
- Research Index Cards, circa 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9-11)
- Interview of Danny Yung, 2022; cuid36867 (Box Electronic Records, Item TW_TAM_817_ER_1)